twingalaxies.com 2003-06-26

# Privacy Statement for Twingalaxies.com

  |  The following statement outlines Twin Galaxies' commitment to protecting your privacy online and details how Twin Galaxies collects and uses personal information that you provide. This policy is subject to change at any time. Please visit this page periodically to review any changes. If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@twingalaxies.com.](mailto:privacy@twingalaxies.com)

## Information Collected

Most of the areas of the Twin Galaxies web site are freely available to all visitors. However, use of certain areas of the web site, such as Live Chat and Discussions require registration with Twin Galaxies. Our registration form requires you to provide contact information (your name and address) and demographic information (your gender and age). As a registered user you can correct and update your user information at any time by following the link marked "Member Info."

This site supplements the information you provide with information received from third parties. We also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer the web site, and to gather broad demographic information (for example, what percent of our users come to us through AOL). 

## Use of Information Collected

This web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.

Your contact information is used to send you information about Twin Galaxies and promotional materials from some of our partner companies. It is also used to contact you directly when necessary. You may decline to receive future mailings: see the "Decline Communications" section below.

Demographic and profile data is also collected by Twin Galaxies. This data is used to tailor your Twin Galaxies experience, including showing content we think you may be interested in viewing, displaying content according to your preferences, and for other purposes. This demographic and profile data is shared with our advertisers on an aggregate basis.

In special cases, we may disclose user information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Twin Galaxies' Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Twin Galaxies web site, other Twin Galaxies users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Twin Galaxies may disclose or access user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

## Contests and Surveys

We occasionally run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information, such as e-mail address, and demographic information, such as zip code or age. We use this data to send users information about Twin Galaxies and promotional materials from some of our partner companies. It is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Our online surveys ask visitors for demographic information such as zip code or age.

Some of the contests or surveys running on Twin Galaxies may be sponsored by third-party companies or may be co-sponsored by Twin Galaxies and a third-party company. In such cases, the third-party company may need to collect personal identifier information from you. If the contest or survey is being co-sponsored, some or all of the data collected may be shared with the co-sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. If you do not want your personal information handled by other companies, you can choose not to participate in the contest or survey. 

## Cookies

Twin Galaxies uses cookies (small files that are stored on your computer's hard drive and are accessible by our web server) to store and sometimes track information about you. For example, we use cookies to ensure that you do not see the same advertisements repeatedly. We also use cookies to deliver content that is specific to your interests and to save your password so you do not need to re-enter it each time you visit our site.

Outside companies display their advertising on our site. These ads may contain cookies, which are collected and maintained by the advertising company. Twin Galaxies does not have access to these cookies. Some of the customer data collected by Twin Galaxies is shared with the advertising companies.

Most web browsers default to accepting cookies from web servers. If you choose, you can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. Please be aware that some parts of the Twin Galaxies web site may not function properly or may operate at a slower speed if you refuse to accept cookies. 

## Links to Other Sites

Twin Galaxies occasionally provides links to third-party web sites. Twin Galaxies is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third-party web sites. 

## Public Forums

Twin Galaxies makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or newsgroups available to its users. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when revealing personal details. Such information can be collected and used by people not affiliated with Twin Galaxies, and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of any information disclosed in these public forums. 

## Children's Guidelines

Twin Galaxies cares about the safety of children online. This site is a general audience web site that complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We only collect personal information from members. Users under the age of 13 are not allowed to become members of Twin Galaxies, but are permitted to use the site with the same level of access to services as any other non-member visitor.

Under COPPA, no web site operator is permitted to require a child under the age of 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary for participation in a web site's activity. Twin Galaxies abides by this requirement. 

## Decline Communications

Our site provides you the opportunity to decline to receive e-mail and other communications from us and our partner companies. This choice can be made at the point where we collect your personal information. If you would prefer not to receive future communications then please modify your account information from the "Member Info" page link. If you would like to terminate your user account, please e-mail us at info@twingalaxies.com. 

## Contacting Twin Galaxies

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy statement, the information practices of this web site, or your dealings with this web site, please contact:Twin Galaxies, LLC Attn: Paul Stokstad 2000 155th Street Fairfield, IA 52556 Phone: (641) 472-3882 x112 Facsimile: (641) 469-6576 E-mail: [paul@twingalaxies.com](mailto:paul@twingalaxies.com)
